pricecheck.co.za 2019-06-30

# Privacy Policy | Compare Prices Online | PriceCheck

PriceCheck (Pty) Ltd, registration number: 2007/013797/07 (hereinafter referred to as " **PriceCheck** ", " **we** ", " **us** " or " **our** ") is committed to ensuring the protection of the privacy of all of all visitors (" **Visitors** ") to our website at www.pricecheck.co.za (the " **Website** ") we well as all persons (" **Customers** ") who have subscribed to any of the services we offer (" **Services** "), whether they be registered 'Users' or registered 'Merchants'. 

This privacy policy (" **this Policy** ") describes the ways in which we collect, store, use and protect your personal information. Throughout this Policy, we use the term "personal information" to describe information that can be associated with a specific person and can be used to identify that person. We do not consider personal information to include information that has been made anonymous so that it does not identify a specific user. 

**You need to read and accept all the provisions in this Policy in order to use the Website and/or Services. By accepting this Policy, you are deemed to have read and agreed with all the provisions thereof. If you do not agree with anything in this Policy, then you may not register and/or use any of the Services**. 

  1. **Changes To This Policy**

We may amend this Policy at any time by posting a revised version on our Website. The revised version will apply to Visitors with effect from the time we post it. **However** we will provide Customers with at least 30 days' prior notice of any such revision by posting notice of the change on the Website and the revision will then apply to Customers with effect from the date indicated in such notice, provided that if a Customer is not happy with the revisions made, he/she/it shall be entitled to terminate the Services subscribed for. 

  2. **General Information About Everyone**
    1. **Types of Information we collect**

As a Visitor, registered User, or Merchant, you agree that we may electronically collect, store and use the following of your information: 

      1. internet usage information, including your Internet Protocol address (" **IP Address** "), browsing habits, click patterns, unique user ID, version of software installed, system type, screen resolutions, colour capabilities, plug-ins, language settings, cookie preferences, search engine keywords, JavaScript enablement, the content and pages that you access on the Website, and the dates and times that you visit the Website, paths taken, and time spent on sites and pages within the Website (" **Usage Details** "); and 
      2. additional information you may provide on a voluntary basis, such as demographic information or information related to your favourite social networking site (eg. the site name, address and description), or information relating to your participation in competitions, promotions, surveys, and/or additional services (" **Optional Details** "). 
    2. **How we collect such information**
      1. _Voluntarily provided by you:_ Optional Details may be submitted by you to us if you decide to upload or download certain content (or products) from the Website, enter competitions, take advantage of promotions, respond to surveys, register and subscribe for certain additional services, or otherwise use the optional features and functionality of the Website. 
      2. _Automatically gathered via various technologies:_
        1. **"Cookies" Information:** When you access the Website, we may send one or more cookies (small text files containing a string of alphanumeric characters) to your computer to collect certain Usage Details. We may use both session cookies (which disappear after you close your browser) and persistent cookies (which remain after you close your browser which can be removed manually) and may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the Website. Please note that the use of cookies is standard on the internet and many major websites use them. Please review your web browser “Help” file to learn more about modifying your cookie settings. 
        2. **Other tracking technology:** When you access the Website or open one of our HTML emails, certain Usage Details may be automatically collected and recorded by us from your system by using different types of tracking technology. 
        3. **Web Beacons:** Our Website may contain electronic image requests (called a "single-pixel gif" or "web beacon" request) that allow us to count page views and to access cookies. Any electronic image viewed as part of a web page (including an ad banner) can act as a web beacon. Web beacons are typically 1-by-1 pixel files (so small that you would likely not realize that they are there), but their presence can usually be seen within a browser by clicking on "View" and then on "Source". We may also include web beacons in HTML-formatted newsletters that we send to opt-in subscribers in order to count how many newsletters have been read. Our web beacons do not collect, gather, monitor or share any personally identifiable information. They are just the technique we use to compile anonymous information about the Website and Service usage. 
    3. **The purpose for which we collect this information**
      1. We may use any **Optional Details** provided by you for such purposes as indicated to you at the time you agree to provide such Optional Details. 
      2. We may use your **Usage Details** to (a) automatically provide you with the latest version of the Pricecheck application on your system; (b) remember your information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you access the Website or Platform; (c) monitor aggregate Website usage metrics such as total number of visitors and pages accessed; and (d) track your entries, submissions, and status in any promotions or other activities in connection with your usage of the Website. 

**NOTE:** Some of our business partners (e.g. advertisers) use their own cookies and/or widgets on our Website and we have no access to or control over such cookies or widgets. (Widgets are interactive mini-programs that run on our Website to provide specific services from another company (e.g. displaying the news, opinions, music, etc) and these widgets may collect certain of your personal information (eg your email address). Cookies may also be set by the widget to enable it to function properly.) Information collected by any such cookie or widget is governed by the privacy policy of the company that created it, and not by Pricecheck. **This Policy covers the use of cookies by Pricecheck only and does not cover the use of cookies or widgets by any third party advertisers on the Website**. 

  3. **Information About Registered Users**
    1. **Types of information we collect about registered Users**

If you are a registered User, you agree that we may also electronically collect, store and use the following of your information: 

      1. name and surname, birth date, gender, location (i.e. country, province and city of residence), nationality, and photographs/images of yourself provided as a profile picture(" **Personal Details** "); 
      2. e-mail address and mobile number (" **Contact Details** "); and 
      3. additional information you may provide on a voluntary basis, which could include demographic information or information related to your favourite website, activities, interests or your participation in competitions, promotions, surveys, and/or additional services (" **Additional Details** "). 
    2. **How we collect information about registered Users**

Your Personal Details and Contact Details will provided by you during your registration as a User and/or thereafter by your actively updating or supplementing such details in your User Account. Additional Details are provided by you on a voluntary basis either directly, or indirectly by means of you linking your User Account to your other social networking profiles, such as your Facebook profile. 

    3. **The purposes for which we collect the information**

We use the information that registered Users provide (or that we collect) to operate, maintain, enhance, and provide all of the features of the Services, and as may be necessary to comply with any relevant laws. **More specifically:**

      1. We use your **Personal Details** to greet you when you access your User Account, to manage and administer your use of the Services and fulfill our contractual obligations; 
      2. We use your **Contact Details** to verify your identity and to inform you of facts relating to your use of the Services (eg. notifications regarding major updates or content you have posted or downloaded from the Website, customer service notifications, and to address copyright infringement or defamation issues) as well as to inform you, subject to obtaining your prior consent, of competitions, promotions and special offers form us and/or our partners and/or affiliates. 
      3. We may use any **Additional Details** provided by you to enhance and personalize your browsing experience on the Website and for such other purposes as may be indicated to you at the time you agree to provide such Additional Details. 
  4. **Information About Merchants**
    1. **Types of information we collect about Merchants**

If you are a Merchant, you also agree that we may electronically collect, store and use the following of your information:

      1. If you are an individual, your full name/s, birth date, identity number and/or passport number, gender, country of residence, and nationality (" **Personal Details** ");
      2. If you are a legal entity, your full name, registration number, country of incorporation (" **Corporate Details** "), and the Personal Details of all your directors and/or office bearers; and
      3. e-mail address, mobile number, and such other contact details as provided by you during your registration application (" **Contact Details** ").
    2. **How we collect information about Merchants**

You provide the aforesaid information directly to us in the application form you submit to us during your registration as a Merchant and thereafter should you actively update or supplement such details in your Merchant Account.

    3. **The purposes for which we collect the information**

We use the information that Merchants provide to operate, maintain, enhance, and provide all of the features and Services provided to Merchants and as may be necessary to comply with all applicable laws. **More specifically:**

      1. we use your **Corporate Details** (or **Personal Details** , as the case may be) to greet you when you access your Merchant Account, to manage and administer your use of the Services, and fulfill our contractual obligations; and
      2. we use your **Contact Details** to verify your identity and to inform you of facts relating to your use of the Services (eg. notifications regarding scheduled system maintenance or downtime, major updates, customer service notifications, and to address copyright infringement or defamation issues) as well as to inform you, subject to obtaining your prior consent, of competitions, promotions and special offers form us and/or our partners and/or affiliates.
  5. **How We Protect & Store Personal Information**
    1. We store and process the personal information of our registered Users, Merchants and Visitors on our computers in South Africa. We use computer safeguards such as firewalls and data encryption, we enforce physical access controls to our buildings and files, and we authorize access to personal information only for those employees who require it to fulfill their job responsibilities. 
    2. You should not divulge your account password to anyone. **We will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited telephone call or e-mail**. YOU ARE RESPONSIBLE FOR MAINTAINING THE SECRECY OF YOUR UNIQUE PASSWORD AND ACCOUNT INFORMATION AT ALL TIMES. 
    3. If you are a legal entity and not an individual, we will liaise only with your named contact or alternative contact provided by your named contact. It is your responsibility to let us know of any changes to your named contact. 
  6. **How We Share Personal Information With Others**
    1. **We may share your personal information with:**
      1. Our holding company, Compare Guru (Pty) Ltd, and other divisions or companies within the group of companies to which we belong, being the Silvertree Internet Holdings (Pty) Ltd group of companies which includes companies registered in countries other than South Africa so as to provide joint content and services like registration, transactions and customer support, to help detect and prevent potentially illegal acts and violations of our policies, and to guide decisions about their products, services and communications. Members of our corporate family will only use this information to send you marketing communications if you have requested their services. 
      2. Our Merchants, but only in the event and to the extent that you, the User, have expressly authorised such disclosure beforehand, other than for purposes of sending you an invoice for any Goods purchased from such Merchant, which disclosed information will be limited to only what is necessary (refer to clause Merchants above).
      3. Merchants sometimes request a User's details in order to follow up with such User as to his/her grievances regarding such Merchant's product/s. Should PriceCheck receive any such request from a Merchant in relation to a User, we will notify the User thereof via email and request his/her permission to such disclosure. Please note that Merchants have their own privacy policies, and PriceCheck will not be held responsible for their operations, including, but not limited to, their information practices, once a User’s personal information has been given to them, either by us with the User’s prior authorisation in accordance with this clause, or by the User directly when transacting with such Merchants. We similarly will not be liable in any way for the manner in which a User may use or disclose any Merchant-related information provided to him/her directly by such Merchant.
      4. Service providers under contract who help with parts of our business operations (fraud prevention, marketing, technology services). Our contracts dictate that these service providers only use your information in connection with the services they perform for us and not for their own benefit. 
      5. Companies that we plan to merge with or be acquired by. (Should such a combination occur, we will require that the new combined entity follow this Policy with respect to your personal information. If your personal information could be used contrary to this Policy, you will receive prior notice.) 
      6. Law enforcement, government officials, fraud detection agencies or other third parties when (a) we are compelled to do so by a subpoena, court order or similar legal procedure; or (b) we need to do so to comply with any law; or (c) we believe in good faith that the disclosure of personal information is necessary to prevent physical harm or financial loss, to report suspected illegal activity, or to investigate violations of our User Agreement and/or Merchant Agreement. 
      7. Other third parties, with your consent or direction to do so.
    2. PriceCheck will not sell or rent any of your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes and only shares your personal information with third parties as described in this Policy, unless we are compelled to do so by law. In particular, in the event of a fraudulent online payment, PriceCheck is entitled to disclose relevant personal information for criminal investigation purposes or in line with any other legal obligation for disclosure of the personal information which may be required of it.
  7. **How You Can Access Or Change Your Personal Information**

You can review and edit any of your personal information at any time by signing in to your User Account or Merchant Account (as the case may be) and clicking the My Account menu in any of the PriceCheck pages. 

  8. **Non-personal Information**

Notwithstanding anything contained in this Policy regarding your information, the following information is not regarded as personal information for purposes of this Policy: 

    1. Permanently de-identified information that does not relate and/or cannot be traced back to you specifically. We may compile, use, share and otherwise process such information as we deem fit. 
    2. Non-personal statistical information collected and compiled by us. We own and retain all rights in such information 
    3. Information which you have provided voluntarily in an open, public environment or forum including (without limitation) any blog, chat room, albums, community, classifieds or discussion board. Because the information has been disclosed in a public forum, it is no longer confidential and does not constitute personal information subject to protection under this Policy. Since such public environments are accessible by third parties, it is possible that third parties may collect and collate and use such information for their own purposes and you should accordingly be careful when deciding to share any of your personal information in such public environments 
  9. **You Consent To The Processing Of Your Personal Information**

By accepting this Policy, you consent to our collection, storage, processing and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Policy. Should you terminate your registration with us and close your User Account, you consent to our retention of the information we have already collected from you for record-keeping purposes only. 

  10. **How You Can Contact Us About Privacy Questions**

If you have questions or concerns regarding this Policy, you should contact us by using the [_Contact Us_](https://www.pricecheck.co.za/contact_us) link on any of the PriceCheck pages
